SANCHIT RASALKAR

Creative Director - Food Media

0

CONTACT

+91 9769341155

✓ sanchitasalkar@gmail.com

Mumbai, India

EDUCATION

2010- 2013

Bachelor of Science in Hospitality & Hotel Administration

Institute of Hotel Management, Catering Technology & Applied Nutrition

SKILLS

- Concept Development
- Art Direction
- Visual Communication
- Creative Vision
- Conceptual Thinking
- Project Management & Leadership
- Collaborative

OTHER SKILLS

- MS Office
- Pre-Production, Production, Post-Production
- Food Styling, Food Designing,
- Recipe & Menu Developer,
- Product R & D
- Research (Food History + Media)
- Baking & Pastry
- Knife work
- Cold Storage & Processed Food Preservation

REFERENCES

Niladri Majumdar (Brand Manager - Rajshri Entertainment) +91 7021271954

PROFILE SUMMARY

A seasoned Creative Director, Professional Chef, & Food Stylist with over 11 years of diverse experience in both kitchen operations & media content creation. Collaborated with celebrity chefs, award-winning food shows, & top food brands, including Chef Sanjeev Kapoor's Khana Khazana. Skilled in culinary arts & media, with a passion for delivering creative contributions

WORK EXPERIENCE

Rajshri Entertainment Pvt. Ltd. Mumbai, India 2023 - PRESENT Creative Director - Food Media (Manager)

- Responsible for creating content with emerging trends and consumer preferences for all digital platforms (4 YT channels & Social media handles)
- Developing Brand Integration Strategies (Brands like, Nestle, Nutrela, etc)
- Concept Development & overlooking scripts for all branded content (Brands like, Thinkitchen, Sunfeast ITC, Reliance, Rasoi Shop)
- Oversaw the creation of engaging content for various platforms, collaborating with internal teams and external agencies to ensure brand consistency and relevance.

Foodlooking Digital Pvt. Ltd. Mumbai, India 2019 - 2023 Head Chef & Content Creative

Impresario Socials (Todi Mills), Mumbai, India Jul '18 - Dec' 18 Jr Sous Chef

Freshyy - Healthy Cafe, Mumbai, India 2017-2018 Head Chef / Operations

Sanjeev Kapoor's Khana Khazana India Pvt. Ltd. 2014-2017 Kitchen Research & Development Chef

California Pizza Kitchen, Mumbai, IndiaJul '13 - Dec' 13

Line Cook

Zabeel Saray, Palm Jumeirah, DubaiDec '11 - May' 12
Trainee

RELEVANT EXPERIENCES & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Confectionery & Pastry at Gajalee, Mumbai, India
- Commis 3 at Renaissance Mumbai Convention Centre Hotel, India
- Business Owner of Saaheb Snacks Centre, QSR, Mumbai, India
- · Co-owned a Food Truck (Chow Down), Pune, India
- <u>TV Shows</u>: EPIC Raja Rasoi Aur Anya Kahaniya, Raja Rasoi Aur Andaz Anokha, Cafe Maria, Gourmet Goes Tribal, National Geography Mega Festivals, Food Food - Cook Smart
- <u>Digital Shows</u>: Hershey's Meethe Bahane, Disney+IKEA Disney Delicious, Nutrela Healthy Plate, Nutrela Nutrilicious Meals
- Ads & Food Styling: Wonderchef, Prestige, Saffola, Daawat, Tata Sampann, Mapro, Hershey's, Pringle, Habit, Ray Cooking Spray, Monginis